Guide to the Agnes DeLano Correspondence, 1925 - 1935 MS2220
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Agnes DeLano correspondence
1925 - 1935
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Cooper, Susan
MS2220
1.5 Linear Feet
This collection contains correspondence written by Agnes DeLano to her relatives during her Western European travels between 1925-1935.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Donated in 2007
Biographical Note
Agnes Delano(1889-1963) was a faculty member of the Mount Vernon Seminary and College. She taught English and Art History at Mt. Vernon from 1929-1954 and Art History and Christian Art at Howard University from 1955-1963.
Delano earned her B.A. and M.A. from the University of Michigan in 1912 and 1913. She taught English in Michigan high schools, Paris, and Boston's Cambridge Haskell School for Girls. It was in Boston that she began her tradition of taking students on summer European tours of art galleries.
For the 20th anniversary of the National Gallery of Art, Delano appeared on coast-to-coast television on the Dave Garroway Today show, conducting a television tour of the gallery.
Agenes Delano wrote "Reflective Writing," a textbook on creative writing, that was published in 1937.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains correspondence written by Agnes DeLano to her relatives during her Western European travels between 1925-1935. Included are handwritten letters as well as photograph postcards, telegrams, menus and other miscellaneous ephemra.
Far from your typical tourist, Agnes DeLano's almost daily letters offer a truly unique perspective. As an educated American female traveling through historically rich Western Europe with a trained eye, DeLano fills each letter with rich details covering impressions of cathedrals and museums visited, locals encountered, recounting of social customs and folklore and observations of contemporary dress. Juxtaposing both her traditional social obligations with her forward and unconventional view of how a visiting American should behave, DeLano's travels are lined with visits to theatres and opera houses, encounters with old acquaintances and journeys to remote monuments and locations off the typical beaten bath.
The order of countires visited per trip is as follows:
1925 - England, France, Italy and returning to France
1926 - France, Italy, France, Italy, France
1928 - France, Italy, France
1932 - France, Italy, Germany, France, England
1933 - Belgium, France, Switzerland, Italy, France, England
1935 - Italy, France, England
The correspondence follows DeLano and her traveling companions over the course of six separate trips: 1925, 1926, 1928, 1932, 1933 and 1935. It is worth noting that DeLano's companions are always female.
Please note that there are other Agnes DeLano files located within the Mount Vernon collection. Please see staff for details.
Other Finding Aids
Also see Finding Aid for MVC0020.MS Mount Vernon Seminary and College Agnes DeLano and Special Collections Room papers. http://library.gwu.edu/ead/mvc0020.xml
Women; Travel; Correspondence; Washington (D.C.); Europe; Women -- History; Mount Vernon Seminary; Mount Vernon College; DeLano, Agnes; Cooper, Susan
- Sailing for England, 07/01/1925 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Winchester/London, England, 07/03/1925-07/08/1925 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Salisbury/London, England, 07/09/1925-07/11/1925 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Stratford, England, 07/14/1925 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Traveling to Paris, France, 07/18/1925-07/20/1925 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Paris, France, 07/20/1925-07/23/1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Paris, France, 07/24/1925-07/28/1925 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Nice, France, 08/02/1925 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Florence, Italy, 08/04/1925-08/08/1925 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Florence, Italy, 08/10/1925-08/12/1925 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Rome, Italy, 08/19/1925 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Paris, France: return trip, 08/20/1925 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Paris, France: return trip, 08/23/1925 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Paris, France: return trip, 08/25/1925 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Michigan, United States: postcard, 09/25/1925 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- New York, United States: start of trip, 06/26/1926 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Holland-America Line, in transit, 06/1926 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Paris, France, 07/11/1926 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Paris, France, 07/14/1926 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Florence, Italy, 07/20/1926-07/21/1926 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Florence, Italy, 07/25/1926 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Paris, France, 07/26/1926 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Assissi, Italy, 07/30/1926 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Florence, Italy, 08/05/1926 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Le Puy/Nimes, France, 08/07/1926-08/08/1926 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Carcassonne, France, 08/10/1926 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Rouen, France, 08/11/1926-08/13/1926 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Paris, France, 08/16/1926-08/21/1926 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Paris, France, 08/25/1926 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- New York, United States: telegram, 06/29/1928 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- New York, United States: in transit, 07/03/1928 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Rotterdam, Holland: in transit, 07/08/1928 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Rouen, France, 07/09/1928 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Paris, France, 07/12/1928 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Paris, France, 07/13/1928 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Paris, France, 07/15/1928 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Paris, France, 07/17/1928 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Paris, France, 07/20/1928-07/21/1928 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Paris, France, 07/23/1928 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Florence, Italy, 08/04/1928 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Florence, Italy, 08/05/1928 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Florence, Italy, 08/07/1928 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Florence, Italy, 08/07/1928-08/10/1928 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Florence, Italy, 08/13/1928-08/14/1928 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Paris, France, 08/17/1928 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Paris, France, 08/20/1928 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Paris, France, 08/21/1928-08/25/1928 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Paris, France, 08/22/1928-08/23/1928 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Paris, France, 08/27/1928 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- New York, United States: setting sail telegram, 06/24/1932 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Rotterdam, Holland: in transit, 06/25/1932 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Rotterdam, Holland: in transit, 07/02/1932-07/03/1932 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- English Channel: in transit, 07/04/1932 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Rouen, France, 07/06/1932 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Paris, France, 07/09/1932 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Paris, France, 07/10/1932 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Paris, France, 07/11/1932 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Paris, France, 07/13/1932 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Paris, France, 07/14/1932 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Paris, France, 07/16/1932-07/17/1932 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Paris, France, 07/17/1932 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Genova, Italy, 07/20/1932 (Box 1, Folder 62)
- Rome, Italy, 07/22/1932 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Rome, Italy, 07/26/1932 (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Florence, Italy, 07/28/1932 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Florence, Italy, 08/01/1932-08/05/1932 (Box 1, Folder 66)
- Venice, Italy, 08/07/1932-08/09/1932 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Munich, Germany, 08/11/1932 (Box 1, Folder 68)
- Paris, France, 08/19/1932 (Box 1, Folder 69)
- Paris, France, 08/19/1932 (Box 1, Folder 70)
- Paris, France, 08/22/1932 (Box 1, Folder 71)
- London, England, 08/25/1932 (Box 1, Folder 72)
- London, England, 08/27/1932 (Box 1, Folder 73)
- London, England, 08/28/1932 (Box 1, Folder 74)
- London, England, 08/29/1923 (Box 1, Folder 75)
- Telegram, 09/02/1932 (Box 1, Folder 76)
- Statendam, Holland: in transit, 06/10/1933 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Antwerp, Belgium, 06/19/1933 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Bruges, Belgium, 06/20/1933 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Paris, France, 06/22/1933 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Paris, France, 06/24/1933 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Paris, France, 06/27/1933 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Paris, France, 06/29/1933 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Paris, France, 06/30/1933 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Paris, France, 07/03/1933-07/05/1933 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Geneva, Switzerland, 07/06/1933 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Montreux, Switzerland, 07/07/1933 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Florence, Italy, 07/10/1933-07/12/1933 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Florence, Italy, 07/13/1933 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Florence, Italy, 07/14/1933 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Florence, Italy, 07/17/1933 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Florence, Italy, 07/20/1933 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Florence, Italy, 07/22/1933 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Florence, Italy, 07/23/1933 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Florence, Italy, 07/24/1953 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  General note
  includes birthday greeting cable
- Florence, Italy, 07/26/1933 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Paris, France, 07/30/1933 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Paris, France, 08/01/1933 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Paris, France, 08/03/1933 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Paris, France, 08/05/1933-08/06/1933 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Paris, France, 08/08/1933 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Paris, France, 08/10/1933 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- London, England, 08/14/1933 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- London, England, 08/15/1933 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- London, England: telegram, 08/16/1933 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- London, England, 08/17/1933 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- London, England, 08/19/1933 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- London, England, 08/21/1933 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- London, England, 08/24/1933 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- In transit, 06/29/1935 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Naples, Italy, 07/07/1935 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Rome, Italy, 07/09/1935-07/11/1935 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Rome, Italy, 07/14/1935 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Florence, Italy, 07/15/1935 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Florence, Italy, 07/17/1935-07/19/1935 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Florence, Italy, 07/22/1935 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Florence, Italy, 07/24/1935 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Venice, Italy, 07/26/1935 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Paris, France, 07/31/1935 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Paris, France, 08/01/1935 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Paris, France, 08/03/1935 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Paris, France, 08/06/1935 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Paris, France, 08/08/1935 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Paris, France, 08/10/1935 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Paris, France, 08/14/1935 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Tours, France, 08/16/1935 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Rouen, France, 08/18/1935 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Paris, France, 08/17/1935 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- London, England, 08/22/1935-08/23/1935 (Box 2, Folder 53)
- London, England, 08/24/1935-08/27/1935 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- London, England, 08/28/1935 (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Ephemera: photograph postcards, 1933-1935 (Box 2, Folder 56)
- In transit, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- In transit, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Vienna, Austria, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- London, England, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Rouen, France, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Rouen, France, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Rouen, France, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Montreux, France, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Paris, France, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Paris, France, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Paris, France, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Paris, France, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Paris, France, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Bremen, Germany, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Cologne/Munich, Germany, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Florence, Italy, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Florence, Italy, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Florence, Italy, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Florence, Italy, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Florence, Italy, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Florence, Italy, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Milan, Italy, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Perugia, Italy, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Ravenna, Italy, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Rome, Italy, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Sienna, Italy, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Geneva, Switzerland, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
- United States/unknown, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Ephemera, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)